Arthur Frank Wertheim Papers, 1862-2005 (bulk 1895-1929) MS 438
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
- Series VI: Circuits
  - Subseries 2: Keith-Albee Circuit,1885-2005 (bulk 1885-1930)
    This series contains printed material including newspaper clippings, advertisements, journal and magazine articles and book chapters. This series includes information on the operations and history of the Keith-Albee Circuit, Keith-Albee Circuit executives and employees, management of the theaters, the theater buildings, and interactions with managers’ associations, unions and performers. Information about Edward F. Albee and Benjamin F. Keith and their families is included.
    - Albee, Edward F.1891-1930, 1953, undated (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Albee, Ethel and Albee, Reed1914-1924 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Albee Jr., Edward playwright1997-2005 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Batcheller, George H.1885-1913 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Boston Herald news clippings (1)1883-1884 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Boston Herald news clippings (2)1885 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Boston Herald news clippings (3)1887-1888 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Bunnell Museum1887-1906 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Continuous performance and the Princess Theater 1900 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Death of E.F. Albee1930 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Early Keith1888-1921 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Europe trip1895-1897 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Female Varieties: Gender and cultural hierarchy on the Keith vaudeville circuit, 1890-1925 (dissertation) 1994 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - General (1)1907-1929, undated (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - General (2)1960-1982 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Goodman, Maurice general counsel1914, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Growth of Keith’s theaters1898-1899 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Hennessy, Daniel1910-1923, undated (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Hillsboro, New Hampshire1885, 2001-2002 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Hodgdon, Samuel K.1896-1898, 1912, 1922 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Independents versus United Booking Offices (UBO) 1909 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Keith’s will (A. Paul Keith)1918-1920 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Keith’s Bijou Theater Philadelphia1889-1896, 1967 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Keith’s theater Chestnut Street Philadelphia1900-1910 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Keith’s theater Union Square1882-1915, 1983-1993 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Keith’s theaters Boston (1)1892-1929, 1975-1983 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - Keith’s theaters Boston (2)1892-1929, 1975-1983 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Keith’s theaters Cleveland and Columbus1907-1908 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Keith’s theaters Philadelphia1900-1914, undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Keith’s theaters Providence1898-1903, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - McElfatrick and Sons architects1966, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Murdock, John J.1909-1915, 1948 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - New York Star photos of Keith executivesundated (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - News and events 1885-18861885-1886 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Palace Theater New York1912-1913, 1977-1991 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Theatrical syndicate1896-1903, 1924, 1940 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - United Booking Offices (UBO)1908-1916 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Vaudeville West: To Los Angeles and the final Stages of Vaudeville (dissertation) 1987 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Willard, Frances E.1896-1897 (Box 21, Folder 12)
- Series VII: Subject Files, 1884-2004 (bulk 1884-1929)
  This series contains printed material including newspaper clippings, journal and magazine articles, book chapters and dissertations, as well as Wertheim’s research notes. A variety of topics are covered including vaudeville audiences and salaries, agents, theater critics, industry publications, censorship, racial and ethnic diversity in vaudeville, and the transition from vaudeville to radio and film.
  - African Americans in vaudeville1906-1927, 1996-2000, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - American performers abroad1897-1912 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - American vaudeville managers: their organization and influence (dissertation) 1981 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Audience studies1896-1914, 1960-1993 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence to Michael Shea1899-1904, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Early agents1884-1910 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Ethnic humor1902, 1971-1992 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - European vaudeville1894-1914 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Houdini notes from abroad1902-1903 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Industry publications1888-1923 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Jewish comedians1910-1911, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous circuits1903-1912 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous topics (1)1883-1898, 1901-1949 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous topics (2)1971-1992 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Playlets1897, 1910-1917 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Research notes from Joseph P. Kennedy collection at the JFK Library 2000-2002 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Rise and fall of the racial comics (dissertation)1963 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - Sunday crusades and censorship1906-1923 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - The Vaudeville Wars: William Morris, E.F. Albee, the White Rats and the Business of Entertainment (dissertation) 2004 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Theater critics1977, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Theatrical hotels1913 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Transition from vaudeville to radio and film (1)1901-1929 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Transition from vaudeville to radio and film (2)1930-1982, undated (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Vaudeville and motion picture shows a study of theaters in Portland, Oregon 1914 (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Vaudeville salaries1906-1915, 1923 (Box 24, Folder 7)
  - Vaudeville - theater in a package1990, 1916, 1971 (Box 24, Folder 8)
  - Wertheim research notesundated (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - Who’s who in music and drama 1914 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Who’s who in vaudeville 19111911 (Box 24, Folder 11)
- Series VIII: News and Events, 1895-1929
  Series note: This series is arranged chronologically.
  This series contains printed material consisting primarily of newspaper clippings, and journal articles that chronicle the news and events of each year. Much of the material comes from industry publications like Variety and the New York Star. Other documents include business records such as legal agreements, union and association meeting minutes and correspondence.
  - 1895 - General1895 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - 1896 - General1896 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - 1896 - Legitimate actors in vaudeville1896 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - 1899 - General1899 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - 1900 – Formation of the Association of the Vaudeville Managers of the United States 1900 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - 1900 - Formation of White Rats1900 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - 1900 - General1900 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - 1901 - General1901 (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - 1901 - White Rats strike1901 (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - 1902 - General1902 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - 1903 - General1903 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - 1903 - Orpheum1903 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - 1903 - Percy Williams/Association of Vaudeville Managers (AVM) feud 1903 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - 1904 - Formation of Western Vaudeville Association1904 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - 1904 - General1904 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - 1904 - Keith expands1904 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - 1905 - Five and ten cent vaudeville1905 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - 1905 - General1905 (Box 25, Folder 18)
  - 1905 - Keith circuit1905 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - 1905 - Orpheum1905 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - 1905 - Sullivan and Considine small time1905 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - 1906 - Combinations1906 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - 1906 - Earthquake and New Orpheum1906 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - 1906 - General1906 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - 1906 - Hammerstein1906 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - 1906 - Keith1906 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - 1906 - Morris1906 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - 1906 - Poli joins the United Booking Offices1906 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 1906 - United Booking Offices (UBO)1906 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - 1906 - Variety Why Artists Should Organize1906 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - 1906 - Williams1906 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - 1907 - Advanced Vaudeville (1)1907 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - 1907 - Advanced Vaudeville (2)1907 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - 1907 - Advanced Vaudeville legal agreements 1907 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - 1907 - Orpheum1907 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - 1907 - Variety1907 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - 1908 - Beck and Orpheum1908 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - 1908 - General1908 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - 1908 - Morris, William1908 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - 1908 - United Booking Office (UBO)1908 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - 1908 - Variety1908 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - 1908 - White Rats1908 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - 1909 - Beck, Morris, Keith feud1909 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - 1909 - Film and vaudeville1909 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - 1909 - General 1909 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - 1909 - Kellermann, Annette1909 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - 1909 - Morris, William1909 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - 1909 - Orpheum1909 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - 1909 - Variety1909 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - 1909 - United Booking Offices and Keith1909 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - 1909 - Voss Agency Bill and blacklisting1909 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - 1909 - White Rats1909 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - 1909 - World Circuit1909 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - 1910 - Cox, George and Rhinock, Joseph1910 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - 1910 - Fox, William1910 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - 1910 - General1910 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - 1910 - Hammerstein1910 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - 1910 - International activities1910 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - 1910 - Orpheum and Beck1910 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - 1910 - United Booking Offices (UBO)1910 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - 1910 - White Rats1910 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - 1911 - Actors Society1911 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - 1911 - Fox, William1911 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - 1911 - General1911 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - 1911 - Hammerstein and the Victoria Theater1911 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - 1911 - Keith-Proctor dissolution1911 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - 1911 - Orpheum1911 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - 1911 - Vaudeville Managers Protective Association1911 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - 1911 - White Rats1911 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - 1911 - Williams, Percy and Tanguay, Eva1911 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - 1911 - United Booking Offices and Keith1911 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - 1912 - General1912 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - 1912 - Hammerstein, Oscar1912 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - 1912 - Keith and United Booking Offices (UBO)1912 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - 1912 - Orpheum and Bernhardt, Sarah1912 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - 1912 - Proctor and Keith, Fifth Avenue Theater1912 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - 1912 - Small time growth1912 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - 1912 - Shuberts1912 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - 1912 - Western Vaudevillle Managers Association1912 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - 1912 - White Rats1912 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - 1912 - Williams, Percy sale of Williams’ theaters1912 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - 1912 - 1913 - Palace controversy1912-1913 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - 1912 - 1915 - Hammerstein, Oscar1912-1915 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - 1913 - General1913 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - 1913 - Keith and United Booking Offices (UBO)1913 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - 1913 - Loews1913 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - 1913 - Martinelli controversy1913 (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - 1913 - Variety blacklist1913 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - 1913 - Western Vaudeville Managers Association (WVMA)1913 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - 1913 - White Rats and The Player1913 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - 1913 - 1916 - Proctor, F.F.1913-1916 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - 1914 - Beck, Martin and the Orpheum1914 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - 1914 - Death of Hammerstein, William1914 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - 1914 - Death of Keith, Benjamin F.1914 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - 1914 - General1914 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - 1914 - Keith and United Booking Offices (UBO)1914 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - 1914 - Tanguay, Eva1914 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - 1914 - White Rats1914 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - 1914 - 1915 - Film houses takeover1914-1915 (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - 1914 - 1916 - World War I1914 - 1916 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - 1915 - Fischer suits1915 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - 1915 - General1915 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - 1915 - Keith and United Booking Offices (UBO)1915 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - 1915 - Orpheum circuit and Beck1915 (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - 1915 - Pantages and Loews1915 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - 1915 - White Rats1915 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - 1916 - Beck, Martin and Orpheum circuit1916 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - 1916 - General1916 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - 1916 - Loews circuit1916 (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - 1916 - Morris returns1916 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - 1916 - National Vaudeville Artists (NVA)and Vaudeville Managers Protective Association (VMPA) reorganize1916 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - 1917 - General1917 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - 1917 - Keith and United Booking Offices (UBO)1917 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - 1917 - Loews circuit1917 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - 1917 - Orpheum circuit1917 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - 1917 - Vaudeville Managers Protective Association (VMPA)1917 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - 1917 - 1918 - White Rats1917 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - 1917 - White Rats strike (1)1917 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - 1917 - White Rats strike (2)1917 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - 1917 - White Rats strike (3)1917 (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - 1917 - White Rats strike (4)1917 (Box 31, Folder 10)
  - 1917 - World War I1917 (Box 31, Folder 11)
  - 1918 - General1918 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - 1918 - Keith Vaudeville Exchange1918 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - 1918 - Loews circuit1918 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - 1918 - Pantages1918 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - 1918 - Paul Keith dies1918 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - 1918 - New York Star1918 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - 1919 - General1919 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - 1919 - Keith, United Booking Offices and Vaudeville Managers Protective Association 1919 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - 1919 - Loews circuit1919 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - 1919 - Orpheum 1919 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - 1919 - Pantages, Alexander1919 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - 1919 - New York Star1919 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - 1919 - White Rats1919 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - 1920 - General1920 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - 1920 - Loews and Pantages1920 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - 1920- Orpheum and Beck1920 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - 1920 - New York Star1920 (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - 1920 - White Rats, American Artists’ Association and Equity1920 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - 1920 - 1921 - Shubert Advanced Vaudeville1920-1921 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - 1921 - General1921 (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - 1921 - Keith1921 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - 1921 - Loews circuit1921 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - 1921 - New York Star1921 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - 1921 - Orpheum1921 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - 1922 - General1922 (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - 1922 - Keith1922 (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - 1922 - Loews circuit1922 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - 1922 - New York Star1922 (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - 1922 - Orpheum1922 (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - 1922-1926 - Impact of radio1922-1926 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - 1923 - Equity1923 (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - 1923 - General1923 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - 1923 - Keith1923 (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - 1923 - Orpheum1923 (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - 1923 - New York Star1923 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - 1924 - General1924 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - 1924 - Keith1924 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - 1924 - New York Star1924 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - 1925 - General1925 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - 1925 - Keith1925 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - 1925 - Loews circuit1925 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - 1925 - New York Star1925 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - 1925 - Orpheum1925 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - 1925 - Pantages1925 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - 1926 - Fox, Loews and Pantages1926 (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - 1926 - General1926 (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - 1926 - Keith and Albee1926 (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - 1926 - New York Star1926 (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - 1926 - Orpheum1926 (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - 1927 - Fox, William1927 (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - 1927 - General1927 (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - 1927 - Keith and Albee1927 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - 1927 - Merger of vaudeville and film companies1927 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - 1927 - Poli circuit1927 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - 1928 - Darling, Edward V.1928 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - 1927-1929 - Decline of vaudeville1927-1929 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - 1928 - Fox and Poli1928 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - 1928 - Formation of Keith-Albee corporation (1)1928 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - 1928 - Formation of Keith-Albee corporation (2)1928 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - 1928 - Formation of Keith-Albee corporation (3)1928 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - 1928 - Formation of Keith-Albee corporation (4)1928 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - 1928 - General1928 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - 1928 - Keith-Albee-Orpheum (KAO) agreement1928 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - 1928 - Keith-Albee-Orpheum (KAO) film trade1928 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - 1928 - Pathe Exchange and DeMille, Cecil B.1928 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - 1928 - Pathe Exchange and Murdock, John J.1928 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - 1929 - Albee, National Variety Artists (NVA), Vaudeville Mangers Protective Association (VMPA) 1929 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - 1929 - Fox buys Loews1929 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - 1929 - General1929 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - 1929 - Keith and Proctors1929 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - 1929 - Pantages and RKO (Radio-Keith-Orpheum)1929 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - 1929 - RKO (Radio-Keith-Orpheum)1929 (Box 36, Folder 9)
- Series IX: Photographs, 1895-1928
  This series contains images of performers, owners, managers, the founders of the White Rats union, theaters, booking offices, and association members and events. Some images come from the book the Papers of Will Rogers.
  - Images from the Papers of Will Rogers (1)1904-1908, 1925-1928, undated (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Images from the Papers of Will Rogers (2)1904-1910, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Miner, Henry (Harry)1898-1902, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Organizations1900, 1920, undated (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Pastor, Antonio (Tony)1880, 1927, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - People1900-1913, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
    Note:101 Ranch Season of 1913 is filed with panoramas above the Arizona/Southwest photo collection.
  - Places1895-1924, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Program of the first performance in any Orpheum theaterundated (Box 37, Folder 8)